

PROFILE:

A designers' aesthetic with 7+ years of designing and coding HTML email messages, has amassed an exact understanding of how to create simply-coded messages that easily pass inbox testing, but also the daily testing of templates that get used in ways outside their intended purpose.

KEY RESULTS INCLUDE:

- Arrange information on a message so that the Call-To-Action is easy to see, read, and act upon
- Transport ideas and styles from larger cross-media campaigns into impactful email messages
- Approach message designs from a user-centered perspective
- Follow appropriate CAN-SPAM requirements
- Working with team members to find the best solution to a marketing need
- Creating Responsive email templates and employ other cutting-edge tactics

SKILLS:

HTML/CSS, Coding specifically for email, including responsive emails, email deployment with various ESP's and inbox testing services, as well as Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator & InDesign.

EXPERIENCE:

Epsilon Americas - Lafayette, CO January 2015 - Present

Email Developer/Designer - Hand-coded multiple email campaigns for various national and international clients. Implemented design updates to fit within larger design standards as well as including cutting-edge code developments like using webkit fonts, show/hide sections of email codes, and responsive/fluid code.

Merkle, Inc - Denver, CO September 2014 - January 2015

(via The Creative Group Aug 2012- Sept 2013)

Email Developer - Updated email files to email best practices. Troubleshooted rendering issues and implemented new coding strategies to quickly transform fixed-width mobile emails to a fluid width for the upgraded iphone 6's wider dimensions. Worked with a team of email developers to solve problems and learn new things.

National Business Media - Broomfield, CO August 2012 - September 2014

(via The Creative Group Aug 2012- Sept 2013)

Email/Web Designer - Implemented an efficient process to reduce errors and increase efficiency. Researched mobile open rates and converted relevant messages to a responsive template that is easy for coordinators to update. Created custom email messages for clients as well as updated emails provided by clients so they would pass basic testing for relevant email clients.

VISIT DENVER (via The Creative Group) - Denver, CO Jan 2012- July 2012

Web Manager - Temporary - Updated and managed existing sites by creating new graphics and inserting new text, photos and forms. Created new HTML emails and edited existing templates to send to membership lists. Created new site designs and graphics as needed.

TargetBase (via The Creative Group) - Irving, TX Oct, 2011 - Nov, 2011

Email Marketing Developer - Temporary - Coded pre-existing email designs in HTML to prepare to send for pharmaceutical client.

Invoke Ideas- Mansfield, Texas 2010-2011

Creative Director/Designer- Maintained and created print, web and email campaigns for various clients. Worked with Account Executive to develop marketing strategies. Responsibilities included branding, concepting ideas, implementing design standards, creating and managing client websites, designing and coding HTML emails, meeting deadlines, and occasional photoshoots.

The Fowler Group - Arlington, Texas 2009-2010

Client Services Representative- Experience as a freelance designer was leveraged by ensuring that communication between design staff, sales staff and client was positive and fruitful. Other responsibilities included Google Adwords, Project Management and Quality Control.

FREELANCE CAREER, 2006-2008:

iBest.net – Wilmington, NC

Created designs for sites based on client brief. Eventually started coding and re-styling existing sites to fit new aesthetics. Edited existing HTML email templates and deployed.

Scott Piner - Wilmington, NC

Created new logo and marketing materials for rising photographer. Redesigned splash page to integrate new marketing materials and produced an email template for client's reuse.

Bollinger Associates – Wilmington, NC

Redesigned new covers for book designs that reflected the new branding and a simpler aesthetic. Colored pencil drawings for comic-book styled children's books.

Energy Performance Solutions – Wilmington, NC

Design logo and identity services. Position and develop new eco-friendly alternative in a new market. Create functional brochure-style website.

BrandFX – Fort Worth, Texas

Redesigned brochures for product family.

Radiant Bridal Consulting - Wilmington, NC

Branding and business card for bridal consulting company.

Reeds Jewelry – Wilmington, NC - September 2006 – May 2007

Redesigned inner-company papers and consumer advertising. Adjusted larger catalogs to miniature for mailings.

EDUCATION:

Rocky Mountain College of Art and Design, December 2002 Bachelors in Fine Arts, Graphic Design Summa Cum Laude, Cumulative GPA: 3.9/4.0